Guide to the Richard Brown Baker Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 2003 Acquisition, 1895-1998; 1; 62.79; (78 boxes)
  - Writings
    - Diaries, typescript, 1952-1960 (Box 20)
      A sampler of diary entries and excerpts from letters showing Baker's development as a collector in New York.
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1041-1102, 1957 July 15-1958 January 14 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1150-1159, 1958 March 10-1958 March 31 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1359-1374, 1959 March 31-1959 April 16 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1427-1486, 1959 May 27-1959 July 31 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 2033-2166, 1958 August 19-1959 October 18 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1508-1586, 1959 September 15-1959 October 22 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1585-1707, 1959 October 23 - 1960 September 26 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 2128-2195, 1959 October 2-1959 October (Box 20)
    - Typescripts, 1957-1959; 6 (Box 20)
    - "New York to London," "A sea voyage," typescript, 1975, 1976 (Box 20)
    - Typescript and correspondence, 1985 (Box 20)
      William Morrow & Company, Inc.'s suggestions to Baker pertaining to publishing a book of his writings, based on submitted excerpts from his journals.
    - Pittsburgh Itinerary, 1988 (Box 20)
    - Drafts, 1952-1976; 16 (Box 21)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1044-1096 (2 copies), 1957 September 16-1958 January (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1144-1166, 1563-1606, 1958 March 4-1958 June 13 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1615-1673, 1958 July 6-1958 July 25 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1674-1766 (2 copies), 1958 July 25-1958 December 1 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1312-1337, 1958 December (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1343-1366, 1852-1857, 1958 December - 1959 March (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1373-1401, 1904-1934 (2 copies), 1959 April 14-1959 May 20 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1422-1520 (2 copies), 1959 May 21-1959 September 15 (Box 22)
    - (3 copies), 1959 May 26-1959 September 30; 3 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 2127-2172, 1584-1617 (3 copies), 1959 October 1-1959 November 6; 2 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1618-1639, 2256-2269 (2 copies), 1959 November 7-1959 December 22 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescript, p. 1650-1707 (3 copies), 1960 January 11-1960 September 26; 2 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescripts, 1940-1958; 2 (Box 22)
    - Diaries, typescripts, 1958-1961; 4 (Box 23)
    - Diaries, typescripts, with corrections, 1952-1960; 3 (Box 23)
    - Incomplete diaries, typescripts, 1952-1960; 2 (Box 23)
    - Revised typescripts, 1952-1955; 6 (Box 23)
    - "Memoirs," typescript, 1953-1960 (Box 23)
  - "Yale Diaries"
    - Typescript, p. 1300-1359, 1958 November 13 (Box 23)
    - Typescript, p. 1618-1639, 1648-1667, 1959 November 7-1960 May 4 (Box 24)
    - Typescript, p. 373-491, 1954 (Box 24)
    - Typescript, p. 493-611, 1954 (Box 24)
    - Typescript, p. 612-728, 1954 (Box 24)
    - Typescript, p. 729-777, 1954 (Box 24)
    - Typescripts, 1956-1959; 10 (Box 24)
    - Typescript, excerpts, undated; 3 (Box 25)
    - Typescripts, 1952-1958; 12 (Box 25)
    - "Souvenirs of Encounter: A Contemporary Art Collector's Story, 1952-1960," typescript (2 copies), 1985 (Box 25)
    - "Souvenirs of Encounter: A Contemporary Art Collector's Story, 1952-1960," typescript (longer version), 1985 (Box 25)
  - "Diaries"
    - Drafts, 1933; 2 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1934; 2 (Box 26)
      Copies of letters, including one original, Baker wrote to his mother, Marion North Brown.
    - Draft and correspondence, 1934 (Box 26)
    - Drafts, 1939-1950; 3 (Box 26)
    - Typescript, 1953 January-1953 August; 2 (Box 26)
    - Typescript, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Draft, 1958; 2 (Box 26)
    - Typescript, 1959 May 21-1959 September 15 (Box 26)
    - Typescript, 1977 (Box 26)
    - Typescript, 1993-1994; 2 (Box 26)
    - Diary, typescript, 1934-1976 (Box 27)
    - Diary, typescript, 1935-1936 (Box 27)
    - Soldier Poets of the Great War, 1988 (Box 27)
    - Historic Houses in New York City Parks, 1992 (Box 27)
    - Tour itineraries of The American Museum in Britain, 1973-1980 (Box 27)
    - Maguire Oil investment, papers, 1949-1986; 2 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous travel papers, 1977-1988 (Box 27)
    - "My visit to Germany of the Grolier Club," typescript, 1970 May (Box 27)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 27)
    - Travel journal-Africa, (empty), undated (Box 27)
    - Investment journal, (empty), undated (Box 27)
    - Town and Country, magazine, 1951 July (Box 27)
    - Typescript, 1959-1974 (Box 27)
      Baker's writings about specific artists and artwork.
    - "In and out of English Houses, Stately and Otherwise," typescript, 1964, 1978 (Box 27)
    - "A Sea Voyage to the bottom of South America," typescript, 1976 February (Box 27)
    - "The diary of a brief journey through the British Isles in September of 1936," bound typescript (Box 27)
    - Diary, draft, 1933, undated (Box 27)
    - Diary, loose papers, 1947-1995; 4 (Box 27)
  - Early Writings
    - "Chapter 1-The Green House Tavern," "The deep voice and the Squeeky voice," "The mystery box,"The landing party," "From office boy to detective," "When will the dead language die?" draft, 1927-1929 (Box 28)
    - "Untitled," "What?" "In London bookshops," "Scorned dignity," "Miss Sallon's will," draft, 1929-1930 (Box 28)
    - "The bandit's cave," "The haunted house," "Caught," "Mr Kelton sorrowfully foresees," "A little blood," draft, 1931, undated (Box 28)
    - "Urbanity and Sophistication," "Establishing peace," "The position of biographer in literature," "A line of type,", 1931 (Box 28)
    - Writing awards, contests, correspondence, 1927-1931 (Box 28)
    - Providence Journal works by Baker, 1926-1927 (Box 28)
    - Award letters, 1927-1931 (Box 28)
    - Yale University, correspondence, 1935 (Box 28)
      Professor Witherspoon to Baker, Honors in English, 1935.
    - National High School Awards 1930-1931, best creative work (Box 28)
    - Scholastic, magazine, 1927, 1931 (Box 28)
    - Clippings, 1927-1931; 2 (Box 28)
      Newspapers in which Baker's stories were published.
  - Foreign Service Material
    Contains writings by Baker during his service with the O.S.S (Office of Strategic Services) Research and Analysis Branch, Europe-Africa Division, Western European Section.
    - "Calling cards received in Spain", 1940 (Box 28)
    - "Narrative of Personal experiences at the Franco-Spanish frontier, Irun-Hendaye," typescript, 1940 June 21 (Box 28)
    - "Memorandum on assistance given by Department of State on the problem of Spain," typescript, 1941 October 23 (Box 28)
    - "Spain," typescript, 1942 April 17 (Box 28)
    - "Spain: Material for Sections III, IV and V of a projected M.I.D. Survey," typescript, 1942 April 17 (Box 28)
    - "Terrain, transportation, and climate of the Iberian Peninsula," typescript, 1942 August 9 (Box 28)
    - "Aspects of Contemporary Portugal," typescript, 1942 October 19 (Box 28)
    - "Pocket Guide to Portugal," typescripts (2 copies), 1943 May 31 (Box 28)
    - "An interpretive account of recent Spanish history," typescript, 1947 (Box 28)
  - Other Writings
    - Yale in the national capital: A history of the Yale Club of Washington 1874-1952 (Box 28)
      Includes correspondence
    - Stairways to another stage, (2 copies), 1952 (Box 28)
    - The Year of the Buzz Bomb: a journal of London, 1944, (2 copies), 1952 (Box 28)
    - Exposition Press Inc., correspondence, 1952 (Box 28)
      Publishing material related to "The year of the Buzz bomb."
    - Essays, written by Baker, 1949-1954 (Box 28)
      "The finest excursion," and "Afternoon of a mind," typescripts
  - Baker Family Papers
    Contains diaries, writings, photographs, correspondence, clippings, scrapbooks, books, articles, and other papers relating to Baker and family history.
    - Address book, undated (Box 29)
      Early entries from Marion Baker, with added entries from Baker.
    - Genealogy notes, undated (Box 29)
    - Ancestral Chart, 1899 (Box 29)
    - Ancestral register for Marion Martin Brown, undated (Box 29)
    - Baker ancestry from Genealogical Record, compiled by George Grant Brownell in 1910, undated (Box 29)
    - Savage, McAuley, and Higgenson family ancestry, 1920 (Box 29)
    - Harvey A. Baker ancestry, undated (Box 29)
    - Colonel Harvey A. Baker, clipping, undated (Box 29)
    - Sisson family ancestry, 1882-1935; 2 (Box 29)
    - Inaugural address of William C. Baker, Mayor of the city of Providence, 1900 (Box 29)
    - Industrial Trust Company information, 1917 (Box 29)
      Harvey Martin Brown was president of the Industrial Trust Company of Providence, Rhode Island.
    - In Memoriam service for Harvey Martin Brown, 1926 July 12 (Box 29)
    - Obituary for Harvey Martin Brown, clipping, 1926 (Box 29)
    - Who's who in 1903, Brown University's 25th reunion, 1928 (Box 29)
    - Baker family, clippings, 1928 (Box 29)
    - William C. Baker, clippings, 1931 (Box 29)
    - Copy of Benjamin Baker's certificate of marriage, 1936 July 2 (Box 29)
    - Diary of places visited by Marion North Brown, 1895-1905 (Box 29)
      Includes postcards
    - Correspondence from Harvey Baker to Marion Brown, 1905-1906; 4 (Box 29)
    - Marriage announcement, clipping, 1907-1908 (Box 29)
    - Harvey Baker, correspondence, 1918-1921 (Box 29)
    - Copy of Baker's birth certificate, undated (Box 29)
    - Family real estate papers, 1914-1924 (Box 29)
    - Harvey M. Baker obituary, clippings, 1926 June 10 (Box 29)
    - Lucy (Sisson) Baker, correspondence, 1934 March 18 (Box 29)
    - Central Congregational Church, correspondence, 1942, May 19 (Box 29)
    - National Casualty Company, correspondence, 1950 November 27 (Box 29)
    - Thomas Black, correspondence, 1951 May 14 (Box 29)
      Letter from Baker to Thomas Black regarding his grandmother's Albemarle County, Virginia property.
    - Appraisal: 252 Bowen Street, Providence, Rhode Island, 1970 October 20 (Box 29)
    - Marion North Brown, correspondence and papers, 1899-1903; 10 (Box 30)
      Correspondence regardsMarion Brown Baker's European travels. Includes related tour guides, maps, rail and shipping line schedules, steamship brochures, ship menus, ticket stubs, concert programs, hotel accommodations, and photographs.
    - "The First 15, a memoir by Richard Baker Brown," typescript, undated (Box 31)
    - "The First 15," typescript, 1949 (Box 31)
    - Biographical papers about Baker, 1929-1993; 5 (Box 31)
    - Photographs of Baker, 1952-1975 (Box 31)
    - Passenger List for the S.S.Washington, United States Lines, 1936 August 26 (Box 31)
      List of cabin passengers and officers from the S.S. Washington departing from New York to Cobh, Plymouth, Havre and Hamburg.
    - Papers pertaining to Baker's rental in Picadilly, England, 1943-1944 (Box 31)
      Includes engraving of Burlington House.
    - Baker's social security card, 1938 December 17 (Box 31)
    - Masonic Masonry certificate of Baker, London England, 1938 October 25 (Box 31)
    - Department of State and Foreign Service papers of Baker, 1938-1949; 3 (Box 31)
    - O.S.S. certificate of identity and membership card, 1944, 1994 (Box 31)
    - Military classification paper, 1944 (Box 31)
    - Student project, 1965 (Box 31)
      "The Richard Brown Baker Museum," Architecture student design for the Rhode Island School of Design.
    - "Pinioning Spain, the unique," periodical, 1954 Autumn (Box 31)
      Baker's review of books published in the Virginia Quarterly Review.
    - Virginia Quarterly Review, correspondence, 1948 (Box 31)
    - "The Problem of Spain today," draft, papers and correspondence related to a talk given by Baker., 1941-1949 (Box 31)
    - Clippings pertaining to Baker, 1955-1962; 2 (Box 31)
    - "Notes on the development of my collection," typescript, undated (Box 31)
    - "Autobiographical sketch of Richard Brown Baker," typescript, 1912-1940 (Box 31)
    - "I review my education," typescript, 1938 (Box 31)
    - "Diary of a young egoist," typescript and related correspondence, 1938 (Box 31)
    - Verse, typescripts, undated (Box 31)
    - "No! Mais non!," typescript, 1939 (Box 31)
    - Virginia Bennett and The Virginia Institute, correspondence, 1939 (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1939-1965 (Box 31)
    - Baker's will, 1935-1956 (Box 31)
    - Booksellers receipts pertaining to Baker's book collection, 1929-1938 (Box 31)
    - Bills, invoices and correspondence pertaining to Baker's art purchases, 1936-1958 (Box 31)
    - Photostatic copies of receipted bills for jade and marble purchases, 1938 (Box 31)
    - Investment portfolio of Baker, 1954-1972 (Box 31)
    - Recipes belonging to Baker, undated (Box 31)
    - Brass handle, undated (Box 31)
    - Appointment book, 1979 (Box 31)
    - Stamps, undated (Box 31)
    - Foreign currency, undated (Box 31)
    - Business cards, 1912-1921 (Box 31)
    - Certification of vaccines, 1912-1983 (Box 31)
    - Membership cards and certificates, 1944-1963 (Box 31)
    - French driving permit of Baker, 1950 March 17 (Box 31)
    - Certificates and awards of Baker, 1986-1993 (Box 31)
    - "In Memoriam, Richard Brown Baker", 2002 (Box 31)
      Includes Grolier club member signatures of attendance, "A message from Lincoln Brownell in Vermont," about the life of Baker.
  - Material Relating to Baker's Youth
    Contains Baker's baby book, correspondence, diaries, schoolwork, typescript drafts of writings, books, photographs, postcards, articles, and other papers relating to Baker's youth. Includes copies of the Delphian, Moses Brown, Yale Students International Union, Model League, Yale Daily News, and Atlantic Monthly.
    - Baker's youth, 1809-1951; 20 (Box 32)
    - Notes on the Cathedrals, travel booklets (2 copies), undated (Box 32)
    - Barcelona, postcards, undated (Box 32)
    - Early compositions by Baker, undated (Box 32)
    - Address books belonging to Baker, 1955-1993; 28 (Box 33)
    - Engagement books of Baker, 1970-1972; 3 (Box 33)
    - Register of visitors to the art collection of Baker, 1957-1998; 2 (Box 33)
  - Bound Diaries
    - December 1928 -September 1938, 1928-1938; 20 (Box 34)
    - September 1938-September 1948, 1938-1948; 23 (Box 35)
    - October 1948-December 1954, 1948-1954; 19 (Box 36)
    - December 1954-December 1961, 1954-1961; 21 (Box 37)
    - December 1961-June 1967, 1961-1967; 20 (Box 38)
    - June 1967-May 1971, 1967-1971; 20 (Box 39)
    - May 1971-May 1974, 1971-1974; 19 (Box 40)
    - May 1974-January 1976, 1974-1976; 14 (Box 41)
    - February 1976-December 1977, 1976-1977; 9 (Box 42)
    - January 1978-April 1979, 1978-1979; 13 (Box 43)
    - April 1979-November 1980, 1979-1980; 12 (Box 44)
    - November 1980-February 1982, 1980-1982; 11 (Box 45)
      Includes Baker's China Tour, September 12-26, 1981.
    - February 1982-May 1983, 1982-1983; 13 (Box 46)
      Includes Baker's South African Tour, February, 1982 and Rome and Egypt, January-February, 1983.
    - May 1983-May 1986, 1983-1986; 13 (Box 47)
    - June 1986-May 1988, 1986-1988; 14 (Box 48)
      Includes notes about fellow passengers aboard the Illiria, departing Campobello, October 1987, with additional notes from Thailand in 1988.
    - May 1988-March 1993, 1988-1993; 18 (Box 49)
    - April 1992-May 1998, 1992-1998; 16 (Box 50)
    - Notebooks
      - 1972-1978, 27 (Box 51)
      - 1978-1987, 30 (Box 52)
  - Other Papers
    Contains other correspondence, papers, photographs, and various writings.
    - "Yale College Class Day," "Yale Mother Goose Rhymes," booklets, 1932-1935 (Box 53)
    - Student photographs, 1935, undated (Box 53)
      Includes photograph of Baker at Oxford.
    - "A sea voyage to the bottom of South America," "Proposed catalogue introduction," typescript by Richard Baker Brown., 1964, 1976 (Box 53)
    - Marion A. Baker, correspondence, 1972 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous cards, undated (Box 53)
    - Baker's calling cards in Spanish, undated (Box 53)
    - Hope Club, member book, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Storage Signage for collection, undated; 3 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1978 (Box 53)
    - "Virginia House an American Place," masters thesis by Gary Inman, 1993 (Box 53)
    - Diary excerpts, by Baker, 1946-1964; 2 (Box 53)
    - "The Christmases in wartime Washington," (1942 and 1943) from the diary of Baker, undated (Box 53)
    - Biltmore House, Asheville, N.C., travel brochure, 1930 (Box 53)
    - Mademoiselle, magazine, 1954 February (Box 53)
    - Clippings, 1976, 1983 (Box 53)
    - "Political Imprisonment in the G.D.R.," by Nigel Baker, 1987 (Box 53)
    - Notebook of Baker, 1971 (Box 53)
    - Excerpts from letters written by Baker, 1941-1942 (Box 53)
    - Diary excerpts pertaining to Pop Art (reproductions), 1962 (Box 53)
    - Correspondence from Baker, 1932, 1995 (Box 53)
      Original and photocopies of letters written by Baker in Geneva to his mother in Rhode Island. Also a copy of a letter written to Margaret Mather Byard "concerning our experiences during a week in Italy in the summer of 1932."
    - Holiday card to Baker from Al Gore's family, 1996 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1981 (Box 53)
      Copy of a clause in Baker's will concerning his artwork, and correspondence with Yale University Art Gallery.
    - Copy of "A message from Lincoln Brownell in Vermont," regarding the death of Baker, 2002 (Box 53)
    - Chinese art and archeology, clippings, 1981 (Box 53)
    - Articles, and other papers of, by, or relating to Baker, his travels and his collection
      - Diary excerpts, drafts by Baker, 1958, 1960 (Box 54)
      - Color slides, 1942-1962; 3 (Box 54)
      - Clippings, drafts, 1946-1990 (Box 54)
      - Travel Photographs, 1938-1997; 20 (Box 54)
        Photographs of Europe, Egypt, Japan, Indonesia, Laos, Vietnam, Thailand, Mexico and the United States visited by Baker.
      - Travel postcards, undated (Box 54)
      - Tarragona, Tossa De Mar, postcards, undated (Box 54)
      - Travel brochure of The Rhine, Germany, undated (Box 54)
      - Travel brochure, Recife/Olinda Brazil, undated (Box 54)
      - Travel brochure of Thailand and map of Bankok, undated (Box 54)
      - Diary excerpts, South America, draft, 1976 (Box 54)
      - Diary excerpts, Greece/Aegean, draft, 1971 (Box 54)
      - Travel notebook, undated (Box 54)
      - West African expedition log, compiled by Tom Ritchie, 1989 (Box 54)
      - Miscellaneous photographs, 1981-1990; 4 (Box 54)
  - Photographs and Photograph Albums
    Box 108 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
    - Marion Martin Baker's scrapbook, 1940 (Box 55)
    - Marion Martin Baker's family photographs, undated (Box 55)
    - Baker family, photographs, 1898-1965; 22 (Box 55)
    - Baker family, slides, 1943-1964 (Box 55)
    - Baker family photograph album, 1900-1924 (Box 56)
    - Baker family photograph album, 1948 (Box 56)
    - Marion North Brown, photograph, undated (Box 56)
    - Baker family photographs, 1931-1937, undated; 4 (Box 56)
    - Clippings, 1930, 1976 (Box 56)
    - Photograph album, 1974, 1989 (Box 56)
      Baker's visit to West Africa and Cambodia.
    - Baker family, negatives, undated (Box 56)
    - Uncut film negatives, 4 rolls, 1939 (Box 56)
    - Photograph album, 1942 (Box 57)
      Baker's trip through the United States. See Box #66 for color slides of the same.
    - Baker photograph album, 1913-1938 (Box 58)
      Baker family photographs and Baker's travel photographs, of Greece and Egypt.
    - Baker's photograph album, 1912-1969 (Box 59)
      Includes Baker's early family photographs, travel photographs of England, Italy, Scandinavia, Germany and New Mexico in 1938; and of Rhode Island after the hurricane of 1938.
    - Baker's family photographs and award, 1916, undated; 2 (Box 60(Oversize))
      Rhode Island Dance award given to Marion North Brown, a photograph of Baker, and three lithographs of William A. Baker.
    - Photograph album, 1976 (Box 61)
      Baker's visits to South America, Europe, and elsewhere
    - Baker's photograph album, 1980-1990; 2 (Box 62)
      Includes exhibition photographs, portraits of Baker, and photographs of his travels to Egypt.
    - Photograph albums, 1977-1989 (Box 63)
      Baker's visit to China and Cape Town, South Africa
    - Yale University graduation class, rolled photograph, undated (Box 64)
      Background, Woolsey Hall.
    - Glass mounted slides of Baker family, 1947, undated (Box 65)
    - Leica Negatives, 1937-1938 (Box 66)
      Baker's trip to Greece and Egypt.
    - Leica negative album, empty, 1937-1938 (Box 66)
    - Exhibit correspondence, slides, negatives and transparencies, 1954-1994; 17 (Box 66)
    - Saul Steinberg art slide strip with portable viewer, undated (Box 66)
    - Baker's art collection photographs, undated; 2 (Box 66)
    - Various portrait photographs of Baker, 1952-1975 (Box 66)
    - Baker travel negatives, 1977; 2 (Box 66)
    - A Semiographic Representation of Art During the Seventies, typescript, 1977; 2 (Box 66)
      Kit Schwartz recorded the personal responses of contemporary artists to the query, "Describe yourself as a person."
      Related Materials
      There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 108.
    - A Semiographic Representation of Art During the Seventies, "Describe Yourself as a Person" by Kit Schwartz, 1977; 1; 01:24:21; Static and a high amount of hiss and background noise can be heard on the tape. The right channel was recorded at a low level. The audio on the left channel is low from 40:57-50:09. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002109974817)
      This audiocassette is related to two folders of material titled "A Semiographic Representation of Art During the Seventies" in Box 66, reference number 769.
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
      Individuals include: V. Acconci, T. Allen, C. Andre, Arman, J. Baldessari, R. Barry, J. Bartlett, J. Beuys, R. Block, M. Broodthaers, S. Brundage, D. Burgy, I. Blurn and M. Ramsden, J. Burnham, J. Collins, M. Compton, R. Cork, O. Fahlstrom, E. Fry, R. B. Fuller, H. Geldzahler, S. Gibson, H. Glicksman, D. Graham, N. Greenwood, J. Hilliard, D. Huebler, I. Karp, J. Kosuth, L. Lippard, R. Martin, J. Masheck, K. Milow, N. J. Paik, J. Reitman
    - Research material, youth information, clippings, 1926-1995; 7 (Box 67)
    - Research material, catalogs, magazines, 1992-1996; 5 (Box 68)
  - Objects
    - Framed photographs of Baker, family and associates, 1900-1990 (Box 69)
    - The Yale Medal, ring and letter awarded to Baker, undated (Box 70)
      Also includes Yale t-shirt
    - Yale memorabilia of Baker, undated (Box 71)
    - Rubber stamping tools of Richard Baker Brown, undated (Box 72)
      "For recording exhibition participants and art works."
    - Wooden box containing artist index cards, undated (Box 73)
  - Printed Material
    - Art International, printed versions, 1962-1970 (Box 74)
    - Art International, printed versions, 1962-1970 (Box 75)
    - Art International, printed versions, 1962-1970 (Box 76)
    - Art International, printed versions, 1962-1970 (Box 77)
- March 2004 Acquisition, 1959-2004; 2; (2 boxes)
  This acquisition consists of artist files kept by Baker, containing printed material, notes, correspondence, gallery announcements, clippings, invoices, photographs, and biographical material about artists relating to his collection of modern art. Notes include personal observations on various artists.
  Formerly Uncat MSS 642.
  - Artist Files
    - Baker's artist list "turned over to the Beinecke Rare Book Library", 2004 March 11 (Box 78)